Henry-Russell Hitchcock
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Photographs, circa 1926-1979, Series 6:; (Box 26; 0.3 linear ft.)
  Photographs of architecture include the work of Frank Lloyd Wright and Gaudi. Also included are interior and exterior views of buildings in Europe and the United States. Photographs of people include Henry-Russell Hitchcock, Chick Austin and Ernestine Carter, Alexander Dorner, Tammy Grimes, Lincoln Kirstein, the Steinway family, and Edgar Tafel. Among the events recorded are Hitchcock with S. Lane Faison and Karl Staley at the GE Lighting Institute, Society of Architectural Historians at the Newport Casino, Hitchcock receiving honorary degrees at the University of Glasgow and Wesleyan University, and a high tea sponsored by the Victorian Society in America. Also found with this series are a small number of negatives and color slides.
  - Architecture (exterior and interior views) (Box 26 (hol))
    - Munich, undated (Box 26 (hol))
    - Nymphenburg, undated (Box 26 (hol))
    - Ocean Springs, 1940 (Box 26 (hol))
    - Paris, undated (Box 26 (hol))
    - Williamsburg, Virginia, undated (Box 26 (hol))
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 26 (hol))
    - By Gaudi, undated (Box 26 (hol))
    - By Frank Lloyd Wright, undated (Box 26 (hol))
  - Art Work (Box 26 (hol))
    - Architectural Drawings, undated (Box 26 (hol))
    - By Maurice Grosser and Ben Nicholson, undated (Box 26 (hol))
  - Events, 1937-1979, undated (Box 26 (hol))
  - People (Box 26 (hol))
    - Hitchcock, circa 1930s-1980s (Box 26 (hol))
    - Others, circa 1926-1970, undated (Box 26 (hol))
  - Places (Box 26 (hol))
    - Cemetery (unidentified), 1953 (Box 26 (hol))
    - Davis Family Houses, undated (Box 26 (hol))
    - Greece (Tourism Organization of Greece, Ch. A. Sfaellos, photographer), 1951-1955 (Box 26 (hol))
  - Miscellaneous Subjects (Box 26 (hol))
    - Bookcases, undated (Box 26 (hol))
    - Bridges, undated (Box 26 (hol))
    - Exhibition Installations, 1968, undated (Box 26 (hol))
    - Family Heirlooms (paintings and furniture in Plymouth and Northampton, Massachusetts), 1968 (Box 26 (hol))
  - Color Slide, Places (Davis Family house), undated (Box 26 (hol))
  - Negatives (Box 26 (hol))
    - Architecture (unidentified), undated (Box 26 (hol))
    - Art Work (Architectural Drawings), undated (Box 26 (hol))
    - Art Work (by Ben Nicholson), undated (Box 26 (hol))